Register of the Ivan D. London papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Inwood Project on Intercultural Communication (European Group of Harvard University Project on the Soviet Social System) Records, 1938-1986
  - B-Schedule interviews (Special Topics Interviews) materials, 1938-1969
    - Religion in the Soviet Union, 1955-1965
      - Research material and reports, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 52: 1-14)
        Includes manuscripts, clippings, and printed matter.
      - Research participants’ reviews on special topics, 1955-1963 (Box-folder 53: 1-9)
        Includes reaction on Slozhnaia situatsiia and other caricatures published in Soviet satirical magazine Krokodil.
    - Rumors on Oleg Koshevoi, 1957 (Box-folder 53: 10)
      Includes clippings and participants' review.
    - Sexual disturbances, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 55: 14)
      Includes clippings from Meditsinskaia Gazeta.
    - Social groups and classes, 1938-1963
      - Analysis of questionnaire answers, 1963 (Box-folder 55: 15-19)
      - Coding, 1960 (Box-folder 55: 20)
        Includes charts and notes.
      - Completed questionnaires, A-Z, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 56: 1-10, 57: 1-12, 58: 1-6)
      - Forms and instructions, 1960 (Box-folder 58: 7-8)
      - Library data, 1938-1956 (Box-folder 58: 9)
      - List of participants, circa 1960 (Box-folder 58: 10)
      - Publications of the Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 59: 1-2)
    - Soviet attitude toward the Germans, 1955 (Box-folder 59: 3-8)
    - Soviet science and education, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 59: 17)
      Includes Russian émigré manuscripts and clippings.
    - Soviet literature and propaganda, clippings and analyses, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 59: 9)
    - Soviet propaganda, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 65: 7-15)
      Includes analysis of Soviet press.
    - Soviet reaction to the downgrading of Stalin, 1956 (Box-folder 59: 10-11)
      Includes survey responses and clippings.
    - Soviet reactions to Radio Liberation's appeal to the Soviet Armed Forces on the occasion of the 37th anniversary of the October Revolution and other events, study conducted in Argentina and Chile, 1955-1963
      Includes participants' responses to the study conducted in Argentina and Chile.
      - Coding, 1955 (Box-folder 53: 11-14, 54: 1)
      - Participants' responses, 1955-1963 (Box-folder 54: 2-9, 55: 1-12)
      - Summary protocols, 1955 (Box-folder 55: 13)
    - "Soviet Re-defection Campaign in the United States," survey conducted by the Tolstoy Foundation, 1955-1962
      Includes correspondence, writings, research memoranda, and printed matter.
      - Nikolai Khokhlov, correspondence, memoranda, and clippings, 1955-1957 (Box-folder 55: 12-13)
        Includes Testimony of Nikolai Khokhlov, Hearing before the Committee of Un-American Activities, House of Representatives, April 17, 1956.
      - Oleg Lenchevskii, correspondence and clippings, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 59: 14)
      - Printed matter and clippings, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 59: 15)
      - Statistical analyses, 1956 (Box-folder 59: 16)
    - Spiritual assimilation of young refugees in Western Europe, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 60: 14)
      Includes informational documents presented by the Council of Europe and clippings, accompanied by a letter from J. Broekhuizen.
    - Suez Canal crisis, survey responses, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 60: 15)
    - Terminal sheet data, circa 1960 (Box-folder 60: 16-17, 61: 1-2)
    - Trotsky's widow on the Radio Liberation appeal to the Soviet people, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 61: 3)
      Includes responses to the discussion paper.
  - D-Schedule interviews (Soviet Psychological Research) materials, Brooklyn College, Center for the Study of World Psychologies, 1939-1968
    Includes clinical interviews and psychological tests, as well as research memoranda, clippings, and correspondence.
    - Biophysics, 1939-1966 (Box-folder 61: 4-5)
      Includes translations of Russian journal articles and other research materials.
    - Engrammatic theory, 1942-1950 (Box-folder 61: 6)
      Includes publications and research material.
    - Index cards, circa 1963 (Boxes 88-89)
      Index cards include handwritten addresses and notes. Most are separated by geographic areas, while some are grouped according to batches, in the original order of the creator.
    - Mailing list, circa 1963 (Box-folder 61: 7)
    - Parapsychology, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 61: 8-15, 62: 1-3)
      Includes correspondence, clippings, research memoranda, reports, and writings.
    - Replies to Ivan London's appeal through Novoe Russkoe Slovo to Russian immigrants to participate in a survey, 1966 (Box-folder 62: 4)
    - Research grant applications, 1963 (Box-folder 62: 5)
    - Research memoranda, series A-G, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 62: 6-11, 63: 1-12, 64: 1-5)
    - "Respondent-Evaluations of the Basic Written Questionnaire of the Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System,", circa 1965 (Box-folder 64: 6)
    - Society for the Psychological Study directory, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 64: 7)
    - Standard invitation letters to potential participants and forms, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 64: 8)
    - Telepathy, research correspondence, A-V, 1964 (Box-folder 64: 9-15, 65: 1-5)
  - "The Interpretation and Validity of Russian and Chinese Political Refugees’ Responses to Questionnaires and Improvement of the Latter as a Research Instrument" file, Department of Psychology, Brooklyn College, 1959-1986
    - Grant applications for research project, 1963 (Box-folder 65: 6)
      Includes correspondence and memorandum.
    - Chinese refugees interviews, 1959-1986 (Boxes 66-71)
      Arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978
      - General, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 71: 10-11)
      - Lam, Hon Leung, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 71: 12)
      - Yeung, Sau-Lun, 1975 (Box-folder 71: 13)
      - Ying, Ho Sang, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 71: 14)
      - Yuen, King-Hsin, 1978 (Box-folder 71: 15)
    - Terminology of Cultural Revolution, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 71: 16)
      Includes correspondence and notes.
  - Reports, seminar notes, and articles on the Project on the Soviet Social System, 1945-1966
    Arranged in two groups: General, arranged chronologically, and alphabetical, arranged by original heading.
    - General, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 77: 1-4)
    - "Aims and Methods of Clinical Interviews with Soviet DP's and Some of the Results," by Helen Beier and Eugenia Hanfmann, seminar notes, 1953 (Box-folder 77: 5)
    - "Annual Report of the Inwood Project on Intercultural Communication, 1956-1957, Parts I-IV," (Box-folder 77: 6-9)
      Includes "External Research Paper," 1955-1957.
    - "Certain Aspects of the Development of the U.S.S.R. Population," by Eugene M. Kulisher, seminar notes, 1953 (Box-folder 77: 10)
    - "The Church and the Soviet Union," by G. Florovsky, seminar notes, 1957 (Box-folder 77: 11)
    - "Classes and Party under NEP (New Economic Policy)," by E. N. Carr, seminar notes, 1957 (Box-folder 77: 12)
    - "Clinical Case Seminar," report, 1951 (Box-folder 77: 13)
    - Critical Letters to the Editor of the Soviet Press, by Alex Inkeles and Kent Geiger, 1952 (Box-folder 77: 14)
    - "Cultural Policy Since Khrushchev," by Max Hayward, seminar notes, 1966 (Box-folder 77: 15)
    - "The Development of the Mass Media in the U.S.S.R.," by Ithiel de Sola Pool, seminar notes, 1963 (Box-folder 77: 16)
    - "Differences in German, Russian, and American Responses to Four Sentence Completion Test Items," by Mildred Geiger, report, 1953 (Box-folder 77: 17)
    - "Domestic and Cultural Aspects of the 22nd Congress," by Merle Fainsod, seminar notes, 1961 (Box-folder 78: 1)
    - "Economics B 2 Schedule," report, circa 1955 (Box-folder 78: 2)
    - "Final Questionnaire," report, 1951 (Box-folder 78: 3)
    - "Glossary of Selected Transliterated Russian Terms,", 1953 (Box-folder 78: 4)
    - "A Guide for the Interviewing of Soviet Escapees," by Alice E. Bauer, special report, 1953 (Box-folder 78: 5)
    - "Guide to the Care of Displaced Persons in Germany," Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Force, 1945 (Box-folder 78: 6)
    - Interpersonal Attitudes of Former Soviet Citizens, as Studied by a Semi-Projective Method, by Eugenia Hanfmann and Jacob W. Getzels, 1955 (Box-folder 78: 7)
    - "Kratkaia zapiska po voprosu Kharvardskoi Ekspeditsii v Germanii," B. Ol'shaskii, report, 1956 (Box-folder 78: 8)
    - "Major Interim Report of the Inwood Project for the Research Year: 1955-1956," by Ivan London (Box-folder 78: 9)
    - "Munich A-Schedule," by B. Ol'shanskii, reports, circa 1955 (Box-folder 78: 10)
    - Observations on Contemporary Russian Behaviour, by Henry V. Dicks, 1952 (Box-folder 78: 11)
    - "Problems of the Social Structure of the Russian Nobility," by Michael Confino, seminar notes, 1966 (Box-folder 78: 12)
    - "Project on the Problem of Communication Between People: External Research Paper,", 1955-1957 (Box-folder 78: 13)
    - "Responses of Former Soviet Citizens to Selected TAT (Thematic Apperception Test) Cards," by Daniel Rosenblatt, 1960 (Box-folder 78: 14)
    - "The Russian Gentry," by Blum, seminar notes, 1958 (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - "The Social System," by Alex Inkeles, 1960 (Box-folder 79: 2)
    - "Some Systematic Patterns of Relationship between Personality and Attitude among Soviet Displaced Persons," by Marc Fried, 1954 (Box-folder 79: 3)
    - "Soviet Friendship Patterns," by Harvey Fireside, seminar conclusion, circa 1957 (Box-folder 79: 4)
    - "The Soviet Patient," by Marc G. Field, final report, 1954 (Box-folder 79: 5)
    - "The State of Soviet Psychology and Some Reflections on Soviet National Character," by Henry A. Murray, seminar notes, 1959 (Box-folder 79: 6)
    - "The Urban Slavic Family and the Soviet System," by Kent Geiger, final report, 1954 (Box-folder 79: 7)
- Writings, 1944-1981
  Include drafts and printed copies of books, speeches, debates, articles, notes, and background materials, arranged chronologically. Also includes editorial correspondence and bibliography.
  - Editorial correspondence from publishers of works by London, 1945-1970 (Box-folder 79: 8-14, 80: 1-18)
    Includes clippings. Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Bibliography, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 80: 19)
  - Reprint requests, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 80: 20)
  - General, 1945-1977 (Box-folder 81: 1-3)
    Includes short journal articles on psychology and education.
  - Psychologists' Misuse of the Auxiliary Concepts of Physics and Mathematics, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 4)
  - Some Consequences for History and Psychology of Langmuir's Concept of Convergence and Divergence of Phenomena, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 5)
  - Psychological Science and Education, by S. L. Rubinshtein, translated by I. London, 1948 (Box-folder 81: 6)
  - The Developing Personality as a Joint Function of Convergence and Divergence, 1949 (Box-folder 81: 7)
  - A Historical Survey of Psychology in the Soviet Union, 1949 (Box-folder 81: 8)
  - The Need for Reorientation in Psychology in the Light of Modern Physics, 1949 (Box-folder 81: 9)
  - Contemporary Psychology in the Soviet Union, 1952 (Box-folder 81: 10)
  - The Scientific Council on Problems of the Physiological Theory of Academician I. P. Pavlov; a Study in Control, 1952 (Box-folder 81: 11)
  - An Application of the Engrammatic Concept, 1953 (Box-folder 81: 12)
  - Research of Sensory Interaction in the Soviet Union, 1954 (Box-folder 81: 13)
  - "A Case Report of Foreign Perception of Research Questionnaires,", circa 1955 (Box-folder 81: 14-16)
  - "Sotsial'naia struktura sovetskogo naseleniia,", circa 1955 (Box-folder 81: 17-18)
    Includes research materials.
  - Soviet Reaction to the Downgrading of Stalin and Some Suggestions for American Broadcasts to the Soviet Union, 1956 (Box-folder 81: 19)
  - Contemporary Religious Sentiment in the Soviet Union, 1957 (Box-folder 81: 20)
  - Publications of the Inwood Project on Intercultural Communication, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - The Soviet Propaganda Image of the West, 1957 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  - Three Flash Studies in Intercultural Communication, 1957 (Box-folder 82: 3)
  - Toward a Realistic Appraisal of Soviet Science, 1957 (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - A Case Study of Historical Analysis Applied to Social Psychological Research, 1958 (Box-folder 82: 5)
  - Evaluation of Some Current Literature about Soviet Education, 1958 (Box-folder 82: 6)
  - The Problem of Contemporary Analysis in History and Psychology, 1958 (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - A Case Study of the Reliability of Research on Foreign Peoples, 1959 (Box-folder 82: 8)
  - Improvement of Mathematics Teaching in Russian Schools, 1959 (Box-folder 89: 9)
  - Instrumentation in Soviet Psychological Research: A Contribution to the Methodology of Tourism, 1960 (Box-folder 82: 10)
  - Improving the Mathematical Training of Soviet Engineers, 1961 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - A Research Examination of the Harvard Project on the Soviet Social System: 1. The Basic Written Questionnaire, 1966 (Box-folder 82: 12)
  - The Revenge of Heaven, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 82: 13-20, 83: 1-5)
    Includes Chinese translation, correspondence, research material, and book reviews.
  - Interviewing in Sinology: Observations on Methods and Fundamental Concepts, 1975 (Box-folder 83: 6)
  - Convergent and Divergent Amplification and Meaning for Social Science, 1977 (Box-folder 83: 7)
  - Socio/Psycholinguistics of the Cultural Revolution: An American Study, 1977 (Box-folder 83: 8)
  - Divergent Amplification and Social Behavior: Some Methodological Considerations, 1981 (Box-folder 83: 9)
- Miriam London (Boulotchnik) Papers, 1945-2005
  - Career file, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    Includes curriculum vitae and record of employment.
  - Correspondence, 1947-2005
    - General, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 72: 2-7)
    - Blumer, Herbert, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 72: 8)
    - Bristol, Helen, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 72: 9)
    - Broyelle, Claudie and Jacques, 1983 (Box-folder 72: 10)
    - Buck, Pearl, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 72: 11)
    - Cantril, Hadley, 1947-1968 (Box-folder 72: 12)
    - Chan, Albert, 1977-2003 (Box-folder 72: 13)
    - Chan, Anthony, 1983 (Box-folder 72: 14)
    - Chan, Peter, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 72: 15)
    - Chang, K-Y, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 72: 16)
    - Chang, Virginia, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 72: 17)
    - Chow, Ching-wen, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 72: 18)
    - Cline, Ray S., 1984-1987 (Box-folder 72: 19)
    - Dolfin, John, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 72: 20)
    - Domes, J., 1968-1986 (Box-folder 72: 21)
    - Durdin, Till, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 72: 22)
    - Fields, Arthur, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 72: 23)
    - Hess, Robert, L., 1987 (Box-folder 72: 24)
    - Ho, Robert, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 72: 25)
    - Hollander, Paul, 1982 (Box-folder 72: 26)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 72: 27)
    - Hormann, Bernhard, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 72: 28)
    - Hsu, Robert, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 72: 29-30, 73: 1)
    - Hughes, Ann, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 73: 2)
    - Jarrall, A. J., 1950-1968 (Box-folder 73: 3)
    - La Dany, L., 1986-1990 (Box-folder 73: 4)
    - Lazzarotto, Angelo S., 1983 (Box-folder 73: 5)
    - Lee, T. L, 1984 (Box-folder 73: 6)
    - Leung, Christopher, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 73: 7)
    - Lindberg, Amanda, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 73: 8)
    - Loh, I-cheng, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 73: 9)
    - Marcus, Kenny, 1971-1984 (Box-folder 73: 10)
    - Metzger, Thomas A., 1979 (Box-folder 73: 11)
    - Mote, F. W., 1983-2005 (Box-folder 73: 11-18)
    - Heuhaus, Richard John, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - Norbu, Dawa, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 74: 2)
    - Penny, Elma, 1994 (Box-folder 74: 3)
    - Petro, Nikolai I., 1972-1979 (Box-folder 74: 4)
    - Poltoratskii, Nikolai, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 74: 5)
      Includes "Pamiati Londona," by N. Poltoratskii, Novoe Russkoe Slovo, 1983.
    - Ryckmans, Pierre, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 74: 6)
    - Schmidt, Albert C., 1983-1985 (Box-folder 74: 7)
    - Sebes, Fr., 1983-1990 (Box-folder 74: 8)
    - Shtromas, Alex, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 74: 9)
    - Siegelman, Phillip, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 74: 10)
    - Sigal, Mark, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 74: 11)
    - Stillman, Whitney, 1978 (Box-folder 74: 12)
    - Thorngate, Warren, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 74: 13)
    - Wadhams, Steve, 1981 (Box-folder 74: 14)
      Includes the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation Sunday Morning talk show script on China's Cultural Revolution.
    - Welch, Holmes, 1978 (Box-folder 74: 15)
    - Wong, C. H., 1974-1979 (Box-folder 74: 16)
    - Wong, T. S., 1975-1983 (Box-folder 74: 18)
    - Wu, Ping-chung., 1964-1982 (Box-folder 74: 19)
    - Yeh, Charles, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 74: 20)
    - Condolence letters on the death of husband Ivan London, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 74: 21-22)
  - China Project records, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 74: 23-24)
    Includes comments, responses, citations, and photographs.
  - Writings, 1951-2005
    - General, 1951-1986 (Box-folder 75: 1-4)
    - Research on Sensory Interaction in the Soviet Union, 1954 (Box-folder 75: 5)
    - "Notes of a Writer," by A. Kron, translated by Miriam London, 1958 (Box-folder 75: 6)
      Includes correspondence and clippings.
    - "Apartment No. 13," by Anna Val'tseva, translated by Miriam London, 1959 (Box-folder 75: 5)
    - Attitudes of Mainland Youth toward Traditional Chinese Customs and Beliefs, 1970 (Box-folder 75: 7)
    - The Making a Red Guard, 1970 (Box-folder 75: 8)
    - The Revenge of Heaven: A Brief Methodological Account, 1970-1974
      Includes correspondence, publishing and copyright agreements, contracts, clippings, and research material.
    - "Internal Chinese Reactions to the Nixon Visit: Seven Clues,", 1973 (Box-folder 75: 9)
    - China's Lost Generation: The Fate of the Red Guards Since 1968, 1974 (Box-folder 75: 10)
      Includes editorial correspondence and readers' reviews.
    - Three Stories from the Chinese Countryside, 1974 (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - "The Humor as a Footnote to Chinese National Character: An Addendum,", 1975 (Box-folder 75: 12)
    - The Shaping of the "Red Guard Mind,", 1975 (Box-folder 75: 13)
    - Little Tiger, Rest in Peace - A Tale of the Cultural Revolution, 1976 (Box-folder 75: 14)
    - The Other China, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 75: 15-16)
    - A Chinese Round Table on the Passing of Mao, 1977 (Box-folder 76: 1)
    - The Education of Mun-yee: A Case Study of a Schoolgirl in Canton, 1977 (Box-folder 76: 2)
    - Prostitution in Canton, 1977 (Box-folder 76: 3)
    - Christ in China, 1978 (Box-folder 76: 4)
    - Great Leap Forward? Expansion of Trade With Mainland China Faces Hurdles, 1979 (Box-folder 76: 5)
    - Hunger in China: The "Norm of Truth,", 1979 (Box-folder 76: 6-7)
      includes correspondence.
    - China: The Generation in the Wings, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 8)
    - A Dissenter's Odyssey Through Mao's China, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 9)
    - Scars of China's Cultural Revolution Linger in Province, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 10)
    - Wei Ching-sheng Defends Himself, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 11)
    - Peking Duck, 1982 (Box-folder 76: 12-13)
      Includes readers' reviews.
    - Bread, Rice, & Freedom, 1983 (Box-folder 76: 14)
    - Broken Faith: Steven Mosher, Stanford, and China, 1984 (Box-folder 76: 15)
    - China's Intellectuals: Their Counter-Education, 1984 (Box-folder 76: 16)
    - China: The Uses of Religion, 1984 (Box-folder 76: 17)
    - China's Party Cadres Hedge Their Bets, 1985 (Box-folder 76: 18)
    - China's Mirages, 1986 (Box-folder 76: 19)
    - "Joining" the Chinese, 1986 (Box-folder 76: 20)
    - Shadows on China, 1987 (Box-folder 76: 21)
    - China: The Romance of Realpolitik, 1989-2005 (Box-folder 76: 22)
      Includes correspondence, notes, and clippings.
- Writings by Others, 1934-1980
  Includes articles, chapters of books, doctoral dissertations, and manuscripts by survey questionnaire respondents. Arranged alphabetically by author name.
  - General, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 83: 10)
  - Manuscripts by Russian immigrants, received from the American Friends of Russian Freedom, Inc. and from the Tolstoy Foundation, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 83: 11-15)
  - Andreev, A. A., 1935-1937 (Box-folder 83: 16)
  - Banov, I., 1964 (Box-folder 83: 17)
  - Bauer, Raymond A., 1952-1953 (Box-folder 83: 18)
  - Baumshtein, A. I., 1968 (Box-folder 83: 19)
  - Bervik, A., 1963 (Box-folder 83: 20)
  - Betkhel, Paul, 1964 (Box-folder 84: 1)
  - Birulia, A. K., 1960 (Box-folder 84: 2)
  - Borodin, S., 1953 (Box-folder 84: 3)
  - Buerakov, Ivan, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 84: 4)
  - Burg, David, 1960 (Box-folder 84: 5)
  - Cantor, Joel, 1952 (Box-folder 84: 6)
  - Denisov, V., 1953-1954 (Box-folder 84: 7)
  - Dimitrov, Petr, 1957 (Box-folder 84: 8)
  - Dudin, Nikolai, 1955 (Box-folder 84: 9)
  - Evronin, G., 1959 (Box-folder 84: 10)
  - Field, Mark, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 84: 11)
  - Filipov, A., circa 1960 (Box-folder 84: 12-15)
  - Garthoff, Raymond, 1961 (Box-folder 84: 16)
  - Gliksman, Jerzy G., 1958 (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Gustafsson, A., 1956 (Box-folder 85: 2)
  - Ingul, V., circa 1960 (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - Kantorovich, L. V., 1960 (Box-folder 85: 4)
  - Khokhlov, Nikolai, 1956 (Box-folder 85: 5)
  - Konstantinov, D., 1959 (Box-folder 85: 6)
  - Kuznetsov, B. M., 1966 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  - Larin, V., 1957 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - Lemeshov, D., 1961 (Box-folder 85: 9)
  - Makarov, I., 1949 (Box-folder 85: 10)
  - Marchenko, B., 1953 (Box-folder 85: 11)
  - Mintz, A., 1958 (Box-folder 85: 12)
  - Petrov-Skitalets, E., 1965 (Box-folder 85: 13)
  - Piaget, Jean, 1956 (Box-folder 85: 14)
  - Raiskii, N., 1947 (Box-folder 85: 15)
  - Razran, Gregory, 1961 (Box-folder 85: 16)
  - Rubenshtein, S., 1940 (Box-folder 85: 17)
  - Rupem, Robert, 1958 (Box-folder 86: 1)
  - Samarin, V., 1957 (Box-folder 86: 2)
  - Sedova, Natal'ia, 1956 (Box-folder 86: 3)
  - Shestov, Leon (Lev), 1962 (Box-folder 86: 4)
  - Sosin, G., circa 1965 (Box-folder 86: 5)
  - Step, Eugene, circa 1955 (Box-folder 86: 6)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, circa 1965 (Box-folder 86: 7)
  - Urbakh, V., 1980 (Box-folder 86: 8)
  - Usko, Isien, 1960 (Box-folder 86: 9)
  - Vlasov, M., 1968 (Box-folder 86: 10)
  - Witt, N., 1963 (Box-folder 86: 11)
  - White, Ralph, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 86: 12)
  - Zenzinov, V., 1945-1956 (Box-folder 86: 13-15)
    Includes book review and notes by I. Grigor'ev.
  - Zuev-Insarov, D. M., 1934 (Box-folder 86: 16)
- Printed Matter, 1949-1971
  Includes pamphlets, brochures, newspapers, magazines, and press clippings. Arranged alphabetically by title, author, or type of material. See also: Oversize Material.
  - American Association for Public Opinion Research, Directory of Members, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 86: 17)
  - Biofizika, tom XIII, Akademiia Nauk SSSR, 1968 (Box-folder 86: 18)
  - Biuleten' Ukrains'koi Vil'noi Akademii Nauk u SSHA, No. 20, 1959 (Box-folder 86: 19)
  - Brochures on Soviet psychology in the Ural Mountains region, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 86: 20)
  - Chasovoi, No. 374, 1957 (Box-folder 87: 1)
  - Clippings on Soviet psychology, education, science, and political events, 1954-1967 (Box-folder 87: 2-3)
  - Digest of the Soviet Ukrainian Press, 1966 January (Box-folder 87: 4)
  - Informatsionnyi Listok, SBONR, Information Bulletin, North American Branch, Russian Liberation Movement (S.B.O.N.R.), Nos. 55 and 60, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 87: 5)
  - International Journal of Parapsychology: Special Issue: Parapsychology in the Soviet Union, Vol. VII, No. 4., 1965 (Box-folder 87: 6)
  - "Nabat (Sturmläuten)," by Il'is Gabudullin Abdulla, Munich, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 87: 7)
  - Newsletters on religion in the Soviet Union, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 87: 8)
  - National Review, 1957 April 6 (Box-folder 87: 9)
  - Plan of Moscow, the Guide Book, 1956 (Box-folder 87: 10)
  - Repatriate Reports, Office of Research & Intelligence, United States Information Agency, 1957 November 29 and 1958 April 10 (Box-folder 87: 11)